

Muhammad Adeeb Azim Bin Mohd Nikman

Kota Bharu, Kelantan, Malaysia

□(+60)143128588 | 🗖 adzimnikman99@gmail.com | 🌴 adeeb-nikman.w3spaces.com | 🛅 adzim99

Summary.

A highly motivated Bachelor of Computer Science with Honours (Information Security and Assurance) graduate with the Google Data Analytics
Professional Certificate, Google Business Intelligence Professional Certificate and pursuing Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills with experience in data collection, cleaning, analysis, and visualization with proficiency in Spreadsheets (Microsoft Excel & Google Sheets), Databases (SQL), Data Visualisation (Tableau & Microsoft Power BI) and Programming Languages (Python & R). Attention to detail and the ability to work effectively in a team where I seek opportunities to apply my skills and knowledge to drive data-driven insights and business outcomes.

Experience

System Analyst

PIPELINE NETWORK SDN. BHD. | FULL-TIME

Petaling Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023
about the designated

• Work alongside clients, subject matter experts (SME), developers and project managers by communicating with them about the designated project to ensure it goes smoothly by documenting the requirements, doing data transformation and creating dashboards. Next, follow through the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) as each phase significantly contributes to submitting deliverables before the deadline.

Analyst Intern

Bangsar South, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

SETEL VENTURES SDN. BHD. | INTERNSHIP

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

• In the SWARM: POS team consists of a lead analyst and interns. The responsibilities are tracking, fixing, documenting and communicating with other departments to solve problems regarding the system and categorizing any incoming flaws using various tools and software. Daily tasks include updating ticket bugs' status and gathering information for dashboard reporting to show the latest persistent day-to-day issues.

Education

Coursera

Online

GOOGLE ADVANCED DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Aug 2023 - Present

• Explore the roles of data professionals within an organization. Create data visualizations and apply statistical methods to investigate data. Build regression and machine learning models to analyze and interpret data. Communicate insights from data analysis to stakeholders.

Coursera Online

GOOGLE BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

May 2023 - Jun 2023

• Explore the roles of business intelligence (BI) professionals within an organization. Practice data modeling and extract, transform, load (ETL) processes that meet organizational goals. Design data visualizations that answer business questions. Create dashboards that effectively communicate data insights to stakeholders.

Coursera Online

GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

• Gain an immersive understanding of the practices and processes used by a junior or associate data analyst in their day-to-day job. Learn key analytical skills (data cleaning, analysis, & visualization) and tools (spreadsheets, SQL, R programming, Tableau). Understand how to clean and organize data for analysis, and complete analysis and calculations using spreadsheets, SQL and R programming. Learn how to visualize and present data findings in dashboards, presentations and commonly used visualization platforms.

Islamic Science University of Malaysia

Nilai, Negeri Sembilan, Malaysia

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH HONOURS, INFORMATION SECURITY AND ASSURANCE

Sep 2018 - Dec 2022

- Grade: 3.70 / 4.0
- Activities and societies: Director for ICT Click 2020, Sports Exco for Information Security and Assurance Committee (ISAC) and Trainer for the LEGO Committee.

TAMHIDI, SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY
May 2017 - Jul 2018

- Grade: 2.86 / 4.0
- · Activities and societies: DOTA 2 eSports Team for the ASASI Games 2018 (TAG18) and Arabic Public Speaking for Arabic Language Programme.

Certifications

Google Business Intelligence Professional Certificate

Coursera | Google

CREDENTIAL ID: CLPDWT9KS9QD

Jun 2023

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Coursera | Google

CREDENTIAL ID: 8S9ZCE7C6XU3

Apr 2023

Projects_____

Curriculum Vitae GitHub

CURRICULUM VITAE ADEEB NIKMAN

Feb 2023 - Present

• Created this Curriculum Vitae using R (Programming Language) with the Vitae package.

Google Business Intelligence Professional Certificate

Tableau

GOOGLE FIBER CASE STUDY

May 2023 - Jun 2023

• Perform ETL in Google BigQuery, then import the data into Tableau and create visualisations for Repeats by Month, Table, Day 1 Call by Market & Day 0 and Day 1 Calls.

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Tableau

CYCLISTIC CASE STUDY

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

• Perform ETL in Google BigQuery, then import the data into Tableau and create visualisations for Number of Trips, Seasonality & Top Trips.

Capturing and Retrieval of Risk Assessment and Risk Control Information for Laboratory Experiment

GitHub

FINAL YEAR PROJECT RISK ASSESSMENT AND RISK CONTROL

Feb 2021 - Jan 2022

• I used the Waterfall Methodology starting from planning, analysis, design, development, testing, implementation, and maintenance for the web-based system to make the project as smooth as possible. The tools and software I have used are Python Programming Language, Django framework and SQL (SQLite for the local host, then moved to PostgreSQL during deployment). I uploaded them into GitHub and Heroku to deploy, manage, and scale the app.

Skills

Data Analytics • Spreadsheets • Databases • SQL • Programming Languages • Python (Programming Language) • R (Programming Language) • Dashboards • Data Visualization • Tableau

Awards

First Class Honours

Islamic Science University of

Malaysia
Dec 2022

• I completed the Bachelor of Computer Science with Honours (Information Security and Assurance) with First Class Honours, where I got the Dean's List Award for seven out of eight semesters in my pursuit of the Bachelor's Degree.

Languages_

Malay

NATIVE OR BILINGUAL PROFICIENCY

English

FULL PROFESSIONAL PROFICIENCY

Arabio

LIMITED WORKING PROFICIENCY

Chinese

ELEMENTARY PROFICIENCY

References_

Associate Prof. Dr. Sakinah Ali Pitchay

sakinah.ali@usim.edu.my

(+60)67986426

ISLAMIC SCIENCE UNIVERSITY OF MALAYSIA • Deputy Dean (Student Affairs & Alumni) | Faculty of Science and Technology